A Finding Aid to the Elisabeth Weber-Fulop papers,1921-1966, in the Archives of American Art AAA.webeelis
Archives of American Art
Elisabeth Weber-Fulop papers
1921-1966
AAA.webeelis
Archives of American Art
0.2 Linear feet
Papers of painter Elisabeth Weber-Fulop measure 0.2 linear feet and date from 1921 to 1966. Biographical material, letters, printed material, and photographs document Weber-Fulop's career and artwork.
Weber-Fulop, Elisabeth, 1886-1966
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in 4 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1964-1966 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Letters, 1936-1966 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 3: Printed Material, 1940-1955 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 4: Photographs, 1921-1965 (Box 1; 9 folders)
Biographical/Historical note
Painter Elisabeth Lisel Weber-Fulop (1886-1966), a resident of Duxbury, Massachusetts, was born in Hungary and raised in Vienna, Austria by adoptive parents. She studied art in Vienna with Ludwig Miclek and in Paris. first at the Academy Colarossi and, later, with Jacques Emil Blanche and Lucian Simon.
At age 18, Weber-Fulop had her first solo exhibition at the Albert Durer Gallery in Vienna. She travelled to the United States to paint a portrait of Austrian opera singer Maria Jeritza and then moved to New York City with her husband, Emil J. Weber, an architect. The couple relocated to Duxbury, Massachusetts, in 1945 where Weber-Fulop remained until her death in 1966.
Weber-Fulop painted portraits, still lifes, and interior scenes. While still in Vienna, she painted the interiors of the palace of Kaiserin Maria Theresa; in New York, she depicted the interiors of the Armor Rooms at the Metropolitan Museum of Art and the Governor’s room at City Hall. Her works were exhibited in Paris, Vienna, Budapest, Milan, and Zurich. In the United States she exhibited at various museums and galleries including the Findlay Galleries in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Elisabeth Weber-Fulop papers were donated in 2009 by the Director and Chief Curator of the Museum of Art, Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute in Utica, New York, Paul Schweizer, who had received them from Weber-Fulop's estate.
Scope and Contents note
Papers of painter Elisabeth Weber-Fulop measure 0.2 linear feet and date from 1921 to 1966. Biographical material, letters, printed material, and photographs document Weber-Fulop's career and artwork.
Painters--Massachusetts; Photographs; Women artists--Massachusetts
- Biographical Material, 1964-1966; Series 1; 2 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consists of obituaries of Weber-Fulop and her husband, Emil J. Weber.
  - Obituaries, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Letters, 1936-1966; Series 2; 2 Folders Box 1
  Most letters are to Weber-Fulop and include Christmas cards and a hand painted New Year’s card. Also found are scattered letters to “Helen” Northrup Squire.
  - Letters and Loose Envelopes, 1951-1966; 1936-1938; undated (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Printed Material, 1940-1955; Series 3; 4 Folders Box 1
  Found are an exhibition catalog, reproduction, and clippings and reviews relating to Weber-Fulop’s works.
  - Exhibition Catalog, Brockton Public Library, Massachusetts, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1940-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, undated; 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reproduction, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1921-1965; Series 4; 9 Folders Box 1
  Photographs consist of images of Weber-Fulop, her artwork, and exhibition installation views. Artwork includes portraits, interiors, landscapes, genre painting and floral painting.
  - Elisabeth Weber-Fulop, undated; 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Installations, undated; circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Artwork, 1921-1956; undated; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11-17)